



michaelsutcliffe86

@gmail.com



674 615 536



www.linkedin.com/

in/michael-sut/



github.com/ Monkfish3000



Barcelona, Spain



English: Native

Spanish: Advanced

Catalan: Preintermediate

Michael Sutcliffe

Junior developer originally from the UK now based in Barcelona. Recent convert to coding and web development having previously worked for almost a decade as an English language trainer. Graduate of Le Wagon Coding bootcamp, I am looking to find a role in an exciting company in which I can develop my new tech skills whilst making the best use of my existing skill sets.

KEY ROLES & ACHIEVEMENTS



LeWagon graduate | HTML CSS JavaScript | React | Ruby | Ruby on Rails | APIs | SQL | GitHub



Providing English language support | Coaching senior Execs | Delivering English language coaching to businesspeople across a wide variety of industry, backgrounds and English level.

KEY SKILLS

Excellent communicator and team player - As a trainer the ability to communicate clearly and efficiently has been indispensable and crucial to my success in all the roles I have held.

Proactive learner - I am always striving to develop new skills, learn how things work and how they can be improved at the same time as constantly refining and expanding my existing skill sets and making the best use of my knowledge and abilities gained in my career to date.

Problem solver - I am able to think on my feet and find solutions to complex problems - whilst learning to code I have become adept at diagnosing potential issues and planning out ways to resolve them.

EXPERIENCE

English Language trainer, Learnlight, Madrid/Barcelona

September 2016 - August 2020

Providing business English classes and in-company language support to a variety of companies ranging from start-ups to multi-national corporations.

I worked with small groups and one-to-one with executives incorporating Learnlight's cutting edge EdTech platform and instructor-led methodology.

Academic coordinator, American Language Academy, Madrid

July 2015 - September 2016

At American Language Academy I was part of a management team responsible for coordinating up to 40 teachers and 1600 students. I provided support, training and orientation to teaching staff. This included developing and directing teacher workshops as well as guiding teachers with problems or challenges they may face.

Key administrator for the LMS platform - coordinating between teachers and dev. team, providing training and resolving technical issues, identifying bugs and bug fixing.

ESL Teacher, American Language Academy, Madrid

September 2013 - July 2015

Prior to joining the ALA administration I worked as an English teacher providing classes to a diverse group of students with varying levels of English.

EDUCATION

Le Wagon Coding Bootcamp, Barcelona

August - October 2020

In the summer of 2020 I completed Le Wagon's coding bootcamp where I gained the fundamental skills and knowledge base of web development and modern tech industry practices- specifically 'agile'.

Oxford International Education, Trinity CertTESOL, London

July 2011

Professional qualification accredited by Trinity College London teaching English as a second language.